Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Government Publications PE.045
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Government Publications
1894-1988
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.045
12 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Government Publications contains pamphlets and publications from federal governments around the world, publications from United States governmental departments, as well as from US state and municipal governments. The collection ranges in date from 1894-1988. Generally, the countries represented were/are related to communism. For instance there are pamphlets from Cuba, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, the Democratic Republic of Vietnam, the German Democratic Republic, and the Soviet Union. The US national, state, and municipal files relate primarily to economics, foreign affairs, labor, social security, and unemployment.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Government Publications consists of pamphlets and publications published by federal governments from around the world as well as the United States. The Collection also includes materials from US state and municipal governments. The materials range in date from 1894-1988, with the bulk ranging from the 1930s to the 1970s.
Series I: Federal Government Publications, 1894-1977, contains pamphlets, reports, brochures, and other publications put out by national governments and their various departments and agencies. Generally, the content of the material relates to communism and anti-communism, economics, foreign relations, and labor. Within the files from Canada there are several publications relating to the working and living conditions of women. There are numerous colorful and graphically striking publications from Communist countries, including Cuba, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, the Democratic Republic of Vietnam, the German Democratic Republic, and the Soviet Union. Included as well are numerous anti-communist publications put out by the Federal Republic of Germany and the Republic of Vietnam.
Series II: United States Government Publications, 1913-1988, contains files from United States governmental departments and agencies. The bulk of the material in the series comes from the Department of Labor, the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and the Works Progress Administration. Of note are several publications on Soviet education and hand-drawn fliers and reports from the Works Progress Administration. There is also material from the Commission on Civil Rights, the National Recovery Administration, the Office of War Information, and the Public Works Administration.
Series III: State Government Publications, 1909-1982, consists of files largely published by state Department's of Labor. These files include reports, pamphlets, and other publications. The bulk of the material in this series comes from New York State. There are numerous reports from the Commission Against Discrimination and the Department of Labor.
Series IV: Municipal Government Publications, 1903-1962, consists of files mainly from New York City, including a list of registered voters from 1912. Departments and agencies represented include: the Department of Labor, the Bureau of Standards, and the Works Progress Administration (WPA). In the WPA files are reports, a supervisor's and foreman's handbook, and reprints of talks given to WPA executives as part of the Executive Training Program. In addition to New York City, this series consists of files from Chicago and Detroit both containing Mayoral reports on race relations.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series. Materials are grouped into folders by government entity and department. Folders are arranged alphabetically within series.
Missing Title
Series I: Federal Government Publications, 1894-1977
Series II: United States Government Publications, 1913-1988
Series III: State Government Publications, 1909-1982
Series IV: Municipal Government Publications, 1903-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Labor -- United States.; Discrimination in employment |z New York (State) |z New York.; Communist parties; Communist countries.; Communism.; Communism -- China.; Vietnam -- Politics and government -- 1945-1975.; Vietnam.; Korea (North); Soviet Union.
- Series I: Federal Government Publications, 1894-1977
  - Algeria: Ministry of Information, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Committee of the Privy Council, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour (Agriculture), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour (Women), 1958 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour (Women), 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour (Women), 1967 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour: Legislative Branch, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Department of Labour: Women's Bureau, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Director of Public Information, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Royal Commission (Spying), 1946 (Box 1)
  - Canada: Saskatchewan: Bureau of Publications, 1945-1947, undated (Box 1)
  - Canada: Saskatchewan: Department of Municipal Affairs, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Cuba: Foreign Ministry Information Department, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Cuba: Ministry of Foreign Relations Department of Information, undated (Box 1)
  - Cuba: Ministry of Labor, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1947-1962 (Box 1)
  - Democratic People's Republic of Korea, c. 1950 (Box 1)
  - Democratic People's Republic of Korea, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Democratic People's Republic of Korea: Department of Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, Ministry of Culture and Propaganda, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Republic of Vietnam: Commission for Investigation on the American Imperialists' War Crimes in Vietnam, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Republic of Vietnam: Consulate General, undated (Box 1)
  - Democratic Republic of Vietnam: Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Republic of Vietnam: Press and Information Department, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1958-1966 (Box 1)
  - Federal Republic of Germany, 1960-1973 (Box 1)
  - France: French Press and Information Service (NY,NY), undated (Box 1)
  - German Democratic Republic, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - German Democratic Republic, undated (Box 1)
  - German Democratic Republic (Statistical Pocketbook), 1961 (Box 1)
  - German Democratic Republic: Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - German Democratic Republic: National Policy I, 1966 (Box 2)
  - German Democratic Republic: National Policy II, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - German Democratic Republic: Office of Information, undated (Box 2)
  - Great Britain, 1914-1915 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain, 1925-1927 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Board of Education, c. 1916 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Board of Trade, 1894-1895 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Information Services, undated (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: British Library of Information, undated (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Central Office of Information, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Colonial Office, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: High Commission for Refugees, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Ministry of Information, 1939-1944 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Ministry of Labour, 1919, undated (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Ministry of Labour: Intelligence and Statistics Department, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Royal Commission on Labour, undated (Box 2)
  - Great Britain: Social Insurance and Allied Services, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Greece: Office of Information, undated (Box 2)
  - Hungary (Constitution), 1949 (Box 2)
  - Hungary: General Statistical Office, undated (Box 2)
  - Hungary: Hungarian National Assembly, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Hungary: Legislation of the Hungarian People's Republic (Washington, DC), 1952, undated (Box 2)
  - India: Board of Industries and Commerce, Mysore State, 1920 (Box 2)
  - India: Information Services, undated (Box 2)
  - India: Ministry of External Affairs, undated (Box 2)
  - India: Ministry of Information and Broadcasting (China), undated (Box 2)
  - Israel: Ministry for Foreign Affairs, 1973 (Box 2)
  - New Zealand: Department of Labour, 1956-1963 (Box 2)
  - Norway: Directorate of Labour Information, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Norway: Royal Norwegian Governments Press Representatives, undated (Box 3)
  - Norway: Royal Norwegian Information, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Norway: Royal Norwegian Governments Information Office, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Poland: Central Board of Planning, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Poland: Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Poland: Ministry of Information, 1942, undated (Box 3)
  - Poland: Polish Embassy (Washington, DC), undated (Box 3)
  - Republic of Kenya, undated (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam, 1954-1958, undated (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam, undated (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam: Ministry of Information, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Republic of Vietnam: Secretariat of State for Information, 1956, undated (Box 3)
  - Rumania: Ministry of Information, undated (Box 3)
  - Russia/USSR: Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1945-1961 (Box 3)
  - Russia/USSR: Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Russia/USSR: State Bank, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Sweden: Ministry of Labour, 1972-1977, undated (Box 3)
  - Yugoslavia, 1947 (Box 3)
- Series II: United States Government Publications, 1913-1988
  - Agency for International Development, 1965, undated (Box 3)
  - Army of the United States: Special Service Division, undated (Box 3)
  - Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure (National Labor Relations Board), circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Civil Service Commission, 1943-1965 (Box 3)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Coat and Suit Code Authority, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Civil Rights, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Industrial Relations, 1915-1916 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Fair Employment Practice, 1944-1946, undated (Box 3)
  - Committee on Public Information, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Public Information, 1918, undated (Box 3)
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, 1961, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Committee on the Judiciary United States Senate, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Agriculture, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Department of Agriculture: Rural Electrification Administration, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Department of Commerce, 1932 (Box 4)
  - Department of Commerce: Bureau of the Census, 1962, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Department of Commerce: Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, 1928 (Box 4)
  - Department of Commerce: Social and Economics Statistics Administration, 1970, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Department of Defense, 1954-1955 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health and Human Services, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare I, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare II, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (catalogs), 1974, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare: Social Security Administration, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Department of the Interior: Bureau of Miners, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
  - Department of the Interior: Mining Enforcement and Safety Administration, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1919 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1940, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1957-1959 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, 1969, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor and Department of Agriculture, 1939, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor (bibliographies), 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor (Bisbee deportations), 1918 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Employment Security: Region I, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Employment Security (unemployment insurance), 1962 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of International Labor Affairs (Directory of International Confederation of Free Trade Unions), 1963 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor-Management Reports, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor-Management Reports, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor-Management Reports, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Standards, 1948-1965 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1928 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1950-1954 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1957-1959 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1965-1968 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics, undated (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics (bulletin), 1965 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics (bulletin), 1966 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Bureau of Labor Statistics (labor history), undated (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Children's Bureau, 1933-1946, undated (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Division of Foreign Labor Conditions, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Division of Labor Standards, 1938-1947, undated (Box 5)
  - Department of Labor: Division of Publications and Supplies, 1937, 1944, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Division of Standards and Research, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Employment Standards Administration, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Employment Standards Administration: Women's Bureau, 1963-1973, undated (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Friends of the Department of Labor (commemorative program), 1988 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor (history), 1963 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor (industrial conference proceedings), 1919 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Labor-Management Services Administration, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Labor-Management Services Administration, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Administration, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Administration, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Administration, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Administration, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Administration, 1970, undated (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Manpower Development and Training Act, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Occupations Safety and Health Administration, 1975-1979 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Office of International Labor Affairs (International Confederation of Free Trade Unions directory), 1958 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Office of Policy Planning and Research, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration and Management (black lung), 1979 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Training and Dilution Service, 1918 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Wage and Hour Division, 1938-1941 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Women's Bureau, 1934, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Department of Labor: Women's Bureau, 1969-1985 (Box 6)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Economic Stabilization Agency, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Economic Stabilization Agency: Wage Stabilization Board, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Economic Stabilization Agency: Wage Stabilization Board I, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Economic Stabilization Agency: Wage Stabilization Board II, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Economic Stabilization Agency: Wage Stabilization Board III, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Emergency Board (Railway Labor Act), 1948 (Box 7)
  - Fair Employment Practice Committee, 1944-1946 (Box 7)
  - Farm Credit Administration, 1939, undated (Box 7)
  - Industry and Labor Advisory Committees, 1942 (Box 7)
  - Information Service, undated (Box 7)
  - Internal Revenue Service (war profits), 1921 (Box 7)
  - International Cooperation Administration, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, 1959-1962 (Box 7)
  - Maritime Administration, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Maritime Labor Board, 1940-1942 (Box 7)
  - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, undated (Box 7)
  - National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor, 1959 (Box 7)
  - National Defense Advisory Commission: Labor Division, 1941 (Box 7)
  - National Emergency Council (economic conditions of the south), 1938 (Box 7)
  - National Housing Agency, 1945 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Administration, 1919 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1936 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1939 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1943-1964 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Relations Board: Division of Economic Research, 1937-1939 (Box 7)
  - National Labor Relations Board: Library, 1956 (Box 7)
  - National Recovery Administration, 1933 (Box 8)
  - National Recovery Administration: Division of Review, 1936 (Box 8)
  - National Recovery Administration: Research and Planning Division, 1935 (Box 8)
  - National Resources Committee I, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - National Resources Committee II, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1940-1942 (Box 8)
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1942-1943 (Box 8)
  - National War Labor Board, 1942-1944 (Box 8)
  - National War Labor Board, 1945 (Box 8)
  - National Youth Administration, 1939 (Box 8)
  - National Youth Administration, 1937-1939 (Box 8)
  - National Youth Administration, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Office for Emergency Management, undated (Box 8)
  - Office of Consumer Affairs, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Office of Facts and Figures, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Office of Intelligence Research, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Office of Price Administration: Consumer Division, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Office of War Information, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Postwar Planning Committee, 1946 (Box 8)
  - President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy, 1962 (Box 8)
  - President's Commission on the Status of Women, 1963 (Box 8)
  - President's Committee on the Equality of Treatment and Opportunity in the Armed Services, 1950 (Box 8)
  - President's Office (occupational safety and health), 1973 (Box 8)
  - Public Works Administration, 1936-1937 (Box 8)
  - Public Works Administration, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - Railroad Administration, 1919 (Box 8)
  - Railroad Labor Board, 1921 (Box 8)
  - Resettlement Administration, 1936 (Box 9)
  - Social Security Administration, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
  - Social Security Board, 1933-1945 (Box 9)
  - Steel Industry Board, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Supreme Court of the United States, 1915 (Box 9)
  - Treasury Department, 1913 (Box 9)
  - War Advertising Council, undated (Box 9)
  - War Department, 1914, 1919 (Box 9)
  - War Production Board, 1940-1943, undated (Box 9)
  - Women's Bureau, 1918-1954 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration I, 1935-1939 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration II, 1935-1939 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration III, 1935-1939 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration, undated (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration: Division of Social Research, 1935 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration: Division of Statistics and Research, 1936-1940 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration: Workers Education Project I, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Works Progress Administration: Workers Education Project II, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
- Series III: State Government Publications, 1909-1982
  - Arizona: State Employment Service, 1958 (Box 9)
  - California: Department of Industrial Relations, 1959-1963 (Box 9)
  - California: Department of Industrial Relations, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - California: Department of Industrial Relations: Division of Labor Statistics and Research, 1954-1962 (Box 9)
  - California: Department of Industrial Relations: Division of Labor Statistics and Research, 1963 (Box 9)
  - California: Department of Industrial Relations: Division of Labor Statistics and Research, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - California: Industrial Welfare Commission, 1925 (Box 9)
  - California: State Commission of Immigration and Housing of California, 1917 (Box 9)
  - Connecticut: Department of Labor: Minimum Wage Division, 1935-1937 (Box 9)
  - Georgia: Department of Labor, 1955-1959 (Box 9)
  - Illinois: Council of Defense, 1918 (Box 9)
  - Illinois: Department of Labor, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Maryland: Commissioner of Labor and Statistics (strikes in men's garment industry), 1932 (Box 10)
  - Michigan: Employment Security Commission, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Minnesota: Department of Education (Italo-Ethiopian War report), circa 1935 (Box 10)
  - Mississippi: Employment Security Commission, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Nebraska: Department of Labor, 1958 (Box 10)
  - New Hampshire: Bureau of Labor, 1913 (Box 10)
  - New Jersey: Board of Mediation, 1966 (Box 10)
  - New Jersey: Department of Labor and Industry, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - New York: Advisory Council on Employment and Unemployment Insurance, 1963 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, 1948 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, 1950 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, 1957 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, 1958 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination I, 1959 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination II, 1959 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, 1960 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination I, 1961 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination II, 1961 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission Against Discrimination, undated (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission for Human Rights, 1962-1964 (Box 10)
  - New York: Commission on Management and Productivity in the Public Sector, 1977 (Box 10)
  - New York: Committee on Farm and Food Processing Labor, 1961 (Box 10)